# **Gail Tyler**

(510) 560-2468 <u>gtyler11@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/gail-tyler/</u> <u>https://github.com/gailedit</u>

#### **OBJECTIVE**

All things are possible through clever Sass and DOM manipulation! The greatest satisfaction in my career has been in creating efficient, effective solutions for customers so they can focus on their goals by working smarter. My solutions up to this point have been solely focused on workflow optimization, and I have always wanted to have a greater impact for my clients, which I am happy to now provide through the development of technical front-end solutions.

### **SKILLS**

**Technical:** HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Python, React, Express, Django, Node, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Atlas, Heroku, VS Code, GitHub, Terminal, Bootstrap, Bulma, Big O, OOP, DOM manipulation, jQuery, REST, Jira,

Other Programs: Salesforce, Slack, Zoom Healthcare Softwares: Allscripts, Epic, Practice Fusion, Cozeva, IDX,

Other Languages: American Sign Language

#### **PROJECTS**

- **w3Schools Revamp** Replication and update of w3Schools homepage and exercises with relational databases and full CRUD functionality, using Node, Express, MongoDB, and Bulma
- **Exploria** Full site build with full auth and CRUD functionality, as well as relational databases using Django, Python, PostgreSQL, and Bootstrap
- **Collective** Social media app for creative collaboration that uses relational databases to match users with projects based on skills. Built with Django, Python, PostgreSQL, and Sass

### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

# Notary Public specializing in Real Estate Loans | May 2020 - present

- Verify the identities of at least 50 clients per week and notarize documents according to California law.
- Ensure 100+ pages of documents are filled out completely and accurately within an average of 45 minutes, and submit the same or next day.
- 100% outstanding customer feedback regarding accuracy, efficiency, in-depth knowledge, and discretion.

# Associate Account Manager, Life-Sciences - CSOFT International | April 2018 - October 2018

- Analyzed and provided project quotes for costs and timelines to clients; communicated project scope to translators (average 3 per project), graphic designers, and other stakeholders across an average of three time zones.
- Coordinated an average of 10 translation projects at any given time for Enterprise accounts, tracking each step of
  project status from kick-off to delivery, with special attention paid to quality assurance.

# Client Account Manager - DeVero, Inc/Netsmart | January 2016 - March 2018

- Provided attentive service to high-value agencies using DeVero's SaaS model electronic medical record in a consultative role to drive product adoption, customer retention, and account growth.
- Troubleshot and escalated technical issues via Jira.
- Collaborated with Product Management team in order to ensure product evolution is aligned with customer needs
  by collecting customer feedback on existing product and their wants/needs, recruiting customers for beta
  rollout/testing, and training on new features and best workflow practices.

#### **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly**, Software Engineering Immersive - December, 2021

American InterContinental University, A.A. Business Administration, Visual Communication - February, 2010